Inventory of the Liang Heng collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Liang Heng collection
1966-1982
2010C13
Liang, Heng, 1954-, collector.
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, printed matter, sound recordings, and photographs, relating to student democratization movements in Hunan Province, China.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical/Historical Note
1954 Born in Changsha, Hunan Province, China
1966 Joined the Red Guards
1977 Admitted to the Chinese Department at Hunan Teachers College
1980 Participated in the 1980 election of the county people's congress Emigrated to the United States
1983 Co-authored Son of the Revolution, an autobiographical account of the Chinese Cultural Revolution
1986 Co-authored Cold Winds Warm Winds Intellectual Life in China Today and After the Nightmare: A Survivor of the Cultural Revolution Reports on China
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, printed matter, sound recordings, and photographs, relating to student democratization movements in Hunan Province, China.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Liang, Heng, 1954-; Student movements--China.; China--Politics and government--1976-2002.
Collection Contents
- Audiovisual materials, undated, bulk 1980 (Box 1)
  - "Inside Story of Qin Cheng Prison, undated (Folder 1)
  - Onsite sound recordings of the student movement, six cassette tapes, 1980 September-October (Folder 1)
    - Tape One: Sound recording of election town hall meeting, Liang Heng, 1980 September 20 (Folder 1)
    - Tape Two: Sound recording of election town hall meeting, Liang Heng, 1980 September 23 (Folder 1)
    - Tape Three: Sound recording of election town hall meeting, Tao Sen, 1980 October 12 (Folder 1)
      Use copy reference number: 2010c13_a_0003052
    - Tape Four: Sound recording of election rally speeches, Chen An-yong, 1980 October 12 (Folder 1)
      Use copy reference number: 2010c13_a_0003053
    - Tape Five: Sound recordings of hunger strike protest at front of the Provincial Party Committee office, 1980 October 13-14 (Folder 1)
      Use copy reference number: 2010c13_a_0003054
    - Tape Six: Sound recording of election debate, Professor Cheng Wen-shan, 1980 September 24 (Folder 1)
  - Students' hunger strike movement in Changsha, Hunan Province, 18 color slides and 3 b/w photos, 1980 (Folder 1)
- Clippings, undated, 1966-1982 (Folder 1)
  - Chinese Cultural Revolution, undated, 1966-1982 (Folder 1)
  - Student movements, undated (Folder 1)